<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>News On This Day</title>
    <link></link>
    <description>1</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <webMaster></webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists describe 'secret of life'</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        Two Cambridge University scientists have published their answer to one of the most fundamental questions of biology - how do living things reproduce themselves?
        In an article published today in Nature magazine, James D Watson and Francis Crick describe the structure of a chemical called deoxyribonucleic acid, or DNA.
      </description>
      <pubDate>25 April 1953</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/ScientistsDescribe.jpg</url>
        <title>Scientists describe 'secret of life'</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farewell to scientist who discovered penicillin</title>
      <link>javascript:void(1)</link>
      <description>
        Sir Alexander Fleming - the man who first discovered the life-saving drug penicillin - has died of a heart attack. He was 73.
        Sir Alexander died suddenly at his home in London. He was married only two years ago to Dr Amalia Coutsouris, from Athens, who worked at St Mary's Hospital in Paddington. His first wife, with whom he had a son, died in 1949.
      </description>
      <pubDate>11 March 1955</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/FarewellScientist.jpg</url>
        <title>Farewell to scientist who discovered penicillin</title>
        <link>javascript:void(1)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albert Einstein dies</title>
      <link>javascript:void(2)</link>
      <description>
        Albert Einstein has died in hospital in Princeton, New Jersey, aged 76.
        The eminent scientist and originator of the theory of relativity was admitted to hospital three days ago with an internal complaint.
      </description>
      <pubDate>18 April 1955</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/AlbertEinstein.jpg</url>
        <title>Albert Einstein dies</title>
        <link>javascript:void(2)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Salk promotes polio vaccine in UK</title>
      <link>javascript:void(4)</link>
      <description>
        Dr Jonas Salk, the world-famous American virologist currently on a trip to the UK, has witnessed a ceremonial polio vaccination in London.
        Margaret Jenkins, aged 21, of Bromley in Kent became the 500,000th person in London to receive the polio vaccine in the first of two injections at the special lunchtime clinic at Guildhall in the City.
      </description>
      <pubDate>5 May 1955</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/DrSalk.jpg</url>
        <title>Dr Salk promotes polio vaccine in UK</title>
        <link>javascript:void(4)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trunk dialling heralds cheaper calls</title>
      <link>javascript:void(5)</link>
      <description>
        Automated telephone connection will make calls easier and cheaper, Postmaster General Ernest Marples has announced.
        From December, Subscriber Trunk Dialling will be introduced in the Bristol area where 18,000 subscribers will be able to make trunk calls without the aid of the operator.
      </description>
      <pubDate>21 May 1958</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/TrunkDialling.jpg</url>
        <title>Trunk dialling heralds cheaper calls</title>
        <link>javascript:void(5)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hovercraft marks new era in transport</title>
      <link>javascript:void(6)</link>
      <description>
        A revolutionary new form of transport which can operate on sea and land has been officially launched in the Solent, off England's south coast.
        The Hovercraft, which has been described as a cross between an aircraft, a boat and a land vehicle, was invented by boat-builder Christopher Cockerell.
      </description>
      <pubDate>11 June 1959</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/Hovercraft.jpg</url>
        <title>Hovercraft marks new era in transport</title>
        <link>javascript:void(6)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK's first trunk call from a pay phone</title>
      <link>javascript:void(7)</link>
      <description>
        The UK's first trunk dialling system from a public call-box has been inaugurated in Bristol today.
        It is the start of a countrywide service that will eventually replace the current Button A and Button B pre-payment system.
      </description>
      <pubDate>5 September 1959</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/UKFirst.jpg</url>
        <title>UK's first trunk call from a pay phone</title>
        <link>javascript:void(7)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World glimpses far side of the Moon</title>
      <link>javascript:void(8)</link>
      <description>
        The Soviet Union has revealed the first pictures of the far side of the Moon.
        The pictures were taken about three weeks ago from Lunik 3, the Soviet satellite launched on 4 October, and transmitted by radio to the Earth, 300,000 miles (483,000 km) away.
      </description>
      <pubDate>26 October 1959</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/WorldGlimpses.jpg</url>
        <title>World glimpses far side of the Moon</title>
        <link>javascript:void(8)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Music of spheres' hails Venus fly-by</title>
      <link>javascript:void(9)</link>
      <description>
        The unmanned US spacecraft, Mariner 2, has taken the first-ever scan from space of the planet Venus.
        The mission took the spacecraft closer to Venus than any had ever been.
      </description>
      <pubDate>14 December 1962</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/MusicSpheres.jpg</url>
        <title>'Music of spheres' hails Venus fly-by</title>
        <link>javascript:void(9)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green light for Channel Tunnel</title>
      <link>javascript:void(10)</link>
      <description>
        The British and French Governments have announced their commitment to build a tunnel under the English Channel.
        Both countries now have the capital and technical skills to bring the project - first mooted 162 years ago - to life but their official statements do not give a definite timetable.
      </description>
      <pubDate>6 February 1964</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/GreenLight.jpg</url>
        <title>Green light for Channel Tunnel</title>
        <link>javascript:void(10)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green light for Channel Tunnel</title>
      <link>javascript:void(11)</link>
      <description>
        A ground-breaking 15-minute live broadcast has shown ordinary Americans what it feels like to be a space probe hurtling to destruction on the Moon.
        The extraordinary pictures from the Ranger 9 moon lander were beamed out directly from the spacecraft's internal cameras.
      </description>
      <pubDate>24 March 1965</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/GreenLightChannelTunnel.jpg</url>
        <title>Green light for Channel Tunnel</title>
        <link>javascript:void(11)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hovercraft deal opens show</title>
      <link>javascript:void(12)</link>
      <description>
        The world's first hovershow has opened with news of a Ministry of Defence order worth £1m.
        The Admiral of the Fleet, Lord Mountbatten of Burma, opened the exhibition today (Wednesday) at Browndown near Gosport in Hampshire. It is expected to attract up to 4,000 official visitors by closing time on Sunday.
      </description>
      <pubDate>15 June 1966</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/HovercraftDeal.jpg</url>
        <title>Hovercraft deal opens show</title>
        <link>javascript:void(12)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large oil field found in North Sea</title>
      <link>javascript:void(13)</link>
      <description>
        The oil company British Petroleum has announced it has struck oil in the North Sea.
        The find will eventually make a huge difference to Britain's balance of payments since almost all of the country's oil is imported.
      </description>
      <pubDate>19 October 1970</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/LargeOil.jpg</url>
        <title>Large oil field found in North Sea</title>
        <link>javascript:void(13)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cannabis 'causes brain damage'</title>
      <link>javascript:void(14)</link>
      <description>
        New studies in America have revealed that smoking cannabis can cause brain damage.
        The US government has funded the cultivation of marijuana in the southern United States for research purposes.
      </description>
      <pubDate>2 October 1974</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/Cannabis.jpg</url>
        <title>Cannabis 'causes brain damage'</title>
        <link>javascript:void(14)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First 'test tube baby' born</title>
      <link>javascript:void(15)</link>
      <description>
        The birth of the world's first "test tube baby" has been announced in Manchester.
        Louise Brown was born shortly before midnight in Oldham and District General Hospital.
      </description>
      <pubDate>25 July 1978</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/First.jpg</url>
        <title>First 'test tube baby' born</title>
        <link>javascript:void(15)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flesh-eating dinosaur resurrected</title>
      <link>javascript:void(16)</link>
      <description>
        A huge new dinosaur skeleton has been unveiled to the media at the Natural History Museum in London.
        Plumber and amateur fossil hunter Bill Walker, 55, found a foot-long claw belonging to the flesh-eating beast at a clay pit in Surrey in January.
      </description>
      <pubDate>19 July 1983</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/FleshEating.jpg</url>
        <title>Flesh-eating dinosaur resurrected</title>
        <link>javascript:void(16)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safety concerns over electronic trike</title>
      <link>javascript:void(17)</link>
      <description>
        An electric tricycle, capable of a top speed of 15 mph, has driven into a safety row on its first day on the road.
        The Sinclair C5 - launched by the computer millionaire, Sir Clive Sinclair - is designed for short journeys around town and can be driven by anyone over the age of 14.
      </description>
      <pubDate>10 January 1985</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/SafetyConcerns.jpg</url>
        <title>Safety concerns over electronic trike</title>
        <link>javascript:void(17)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hubble telescope takes off for space</title>
      <link>javascript:void(18)</link>
      <description>
        The American space agency Nasa has successfully launched the space shuttle Discovery from Cape Canaveral in Florida on its historic mission to carry the Hubble space telescope into orbit 380 miles (611.5 km) above the Earth.
        The telescope will operate from high above the atmosphere, thus avoiding the interference which limits ground-based telescopes.
      </description>
      <pubDate>24 April 1990</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/HubbleTelescope.jpg</url>
        <title>Hubble telescope takes off for space</title>
        <link>javascript:void(18)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Royal approval for oil drilling at Windsor</title>
      <link>javascript:void(19)</link>
      <description>
        The Queen has given the go ahead for oil drilling to take place in the grounds of Windsor Castle.
        Exploratory work could get underway as early as next summer at the popular tourist spot.
      </description>
      <pubDate>6 December 1994</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/RoyalApproval.jpg</url>
        <title>Royal approval for oil drilling at Windsor</title>
        <link>javascript:void(19)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First GM food goes on sale in UK</title>
      <link>javascript:void(20)</link>
      <description>
        The first genetically modified, or GM, food goes on sale today in British supermarkets.
        Genetically modified tomato puree, which will be available in Safeway and Sainsbury stores, has been produced from fruit which has had the rotting gene removed.
      </description>
      <pubDate>5 February 1996</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/FirstGM.jpg</url>
        <title>First GM food goes on sale in UK</title>
        <link>javascript:void(20)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dolly the sheep is cloned</title>
      <link>javascript:void(21)</link>
      <description>
        Scientists in Scotland have announced the birth of the world's first successfully cloned mammal, Dolly the sheep.
        Dolly, who was created at the Roslin Institute in Edinburgh, was actually born on 5 July 1996 although her arrival has only just been revealed.
      </description>
      <pubDate>22 February 1997</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/DollySheep.jpg</url>
        <title>Dolly the sheep is cloned</title>
        <link>javascript:void(21)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists highlight hazards of GM food</title>
      <link>javascript:void(22)</link>
      <description>
        A group of international scientists has reinforced warnings genetically modified food may be damaging to health.
        The 20 independent scientists have signed a memorandum in support of Arpad Pusztai who was forced to retire last year over his revelations about the effects of biologically altered potatoes on laboratory rats.
      </description>
      <pubDate>12 February 1999</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/ScientistsHighlight.jpg</url>
        <title>Scientists highlight hazards of GM food</title>
        <link>javascript:void(22)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GM blunder leaves farmers in uproar</title>
      <link>javascript:void(23)</link>
      <description>
        Scottish farmers who accidentally planted genetically modified seeds have said they will fight for compensation after the UK Government advised them to dig up the crop.
        It is believed thousands of hectares of land in Scotland have been sown with the GM contaminated oil seed rape.
      </description>
      <pubDate>27 May 2000</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/GMBlunder.jpg</url>
        <title>GM blunder leaves farmers in uproar</title>
        <link>javascript:void(23)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists discover why we are here</title>
      <link>javascript:void(24)</link>
      <description>
        A Californian University has thrown more light on why the Big Bang works after nearly 40 years of world-wide research.
        Most scientists accept that the universe began with the Big Bang and the existence - in equal amounts - of matter and anti-matter.
      </description>
      <pubDate>9 July 2001</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/ScientistsDiscover.jpg</url>
        <title>Scientists discover why we are here</title>
        <link>javascript:void(24)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mars space probe disappears</title>
      <link>javascript:void(25)</link>
      <description>
        Scientists have failed to make contact with the British-built Mars probe, Beagle 2, which should have landed on the planet early today.
        The £35m ($62m) spacecraft was scheduled to touch down at 0254 GMT after its seven-month flight to the Red Planet.
      </description>
      <pubDate>25 December 2003</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/MarsSpace.jpg</url>
        <title>Mars space probe disappears</title>
        <link>javascript:void(25)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>