<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>News</title>
    <link></link>
    <description>1</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <webMaster></webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>UK's first trunk call from a pay phone</title>
      <link>javascript:void(7)</link>
      <description>
        The UK's first trunk dialling system from a public call-box has been inaugurated in Bristol today.
        It is the start of a countrywide service that will eventually replace the current Button A and Button B pre-payment system.
      </description>
      <pubDate>5 September 1959</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/UKFirst.jpg</url>
        <title>UK's first trunk call from a pay phone</title>
        <link>javascript:void(7)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World glimpses far side of the Moon</title>
      <link>javascript:void(8)</link>
      <description>
        The Soviet Union has revealed the first pictures of the far side of the Moon.
        The pictures were taken about three weeks ago from Lunik 3, the Soviet satellite launched on 4 October, and transmitted by radio to the Earth, 300,000 miles (483,000 km) away.
      </description>
      <pubDate>26 October 1959</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/WorldGlimpses.jpg</url>
        <title>World glimpses far side of the Moon</title>
        <link>javascript:void(8)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Music of spheres' hails Venus fly-by</title>
      <link>javascript:void(9)</link>
      <description>
        The unmanned US spacecraft, Mariner 2, has taken the first-ever scan from space of the planet Venus.
        The mission took the spacecraft closer to Venus than any had ever been.
      </description>
      <pubDate>14 December 1962</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/MusicSpheres.jpg</url>
        <title>'Music of spheres' hails Venus fly-by</title>
        <link>javascript:void(9)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green light for Channel Tunnel</title>
      <link>javascript:void(10)</link>
      <description>
        The British and French Governments have announced their commitment to build a tunnel under the English Channel.
        Both countries now have the capital and technical skills to bring the project - first mooted 162 years ago - to life but their official statements do not give a definite timetable.
      </description>
      <pubDate>6 February 1964</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/GreenLight.jpg</url>
        <title>Green light for Channel Tunnel</title>
        <link>javascript:void(10)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green light for Channel Tunnel</title>
      <link>javascript:void(11)</link>
      <description>
        A ground-breaking 15-minute live broadcast has shown ordinary Americans what it feels like to be a space probe hurtling to destruction on the Moon.
        The extraordinary pictures from the Ranger 9 moon lander were beamed out directly from the spacecraft's internal cameras.
      </description>
      <pubDate>24 March 1965</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/OnThisDay/GreenLightChannelTunnel.jpg</url>
        <title>Green light for Channel Tunnel</title>
        <link>javascript:void(11)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>