<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>News</title>
    <link></link>
    <description>1</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <webMaster></webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>Soviets Launch First Man in Space</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        Major Yuri Alexeyevich Gagarin was fired from the Baikonur launch pad in Kazakhstan, Soviet central Asia, in the space craft Vostok (East).
        Gagarin orbited the Earth for 108 minutes travelling at more than 17,000 miles per hour (27,000 kilometres per hour) before landing at an undisclosed location.
      </description>
      <category>Space</category>
      <pubDate>12 April 1961</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/gagarin.jpg</url>
        <title>Mars</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manchester Utd win European Cup</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        Manchester United have become the first English club to win the European Cup beating Portuguese side Benfica by four goals to one.
        Ten years after the Munich air crash, which killed eight of Matt Busby's young team, Manchester United have reached the pinnacle of European football.
      </description>
      <category>Sport</category>
      <pubDate>29 May 1968</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/manchester.jpg</url>
        <title>greece</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronaut Neil Armstrong's Speech on the Moon</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        The first human journey to the surface of the Moon began at Pad A, Launch Complex 39, Kennedy Space Center, Florida with the liftoff of Apollo 11 on a Saturn V booster at 9:32 a.m. EDT (13:32 UT) on a clear sunny Wednesday, 16 July 1969.
        The footprints left by the astronauts in the Sea of Tranquility are more permanent than most solid structures on Earth. Barring a chance meteorite impact, these impressions in the lunar soil will probably last for millions of years.
      </description>
      <category>Space</category>
      <pubDate>16 July 1969</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/earthrise.jpg</url>
        <title>Astronaut</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muhammad Ali wins 'Thrilla in Manila'</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        US boxer Muhammad Ali has retained the world heavyweight boxing championship after defeating his arch-rival, Joe Frazier, in their third and arguably greatest fight.
        The so-called "Thrilla in Manilla" lasted 14 rounds before Frazier's trainer, Eddie Futch, finally persuaded him to call it a day.
      </description>
      <category>Sport</category>
      <pubDate>1 October 1975</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/muhammad.jpg</url>
        <title>muhammad</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Johnson stripped of Olympic gold</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        Sprinter Ben Johnson has been sent home from the Seoul Olympic Games in disgrace.
        The Canadian has also been stripped of his 100m gold medal after testing positive for drugs
      </description>
      <category>Sport</category>
      <pubDate>27 September 1988</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/johnson.jpg</url>
        <title>johnson</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists Clone Sheep</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        Dolly the sheep, who became famous as the first mammal to be cloned from an adult cell. Dolly was named after the country-western singer Dolly Parton, made headlines worldwide in 1996 when she became the first mammal to be cloned with DNA taken from an adult cell.
      </description>
      <category>Science</category>
      <pubDate>29 October 2001</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/dolly.jpg</url>
        <title>sheep</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Terminator takes on California</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        The film star Arnold Schwarzenegger has been elected governor of California, ousting the incumbent, Gray Davis, three years before his term was due to end.
        It is the first time in the state's history that a governor has been sacked mid-term.
        With most of the ballots counted, Mr Schwarzenegger has won almost 48% of the vote.
      </description>
      <category>Elections</category>
      <pubDate>8 October 2003</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/terminator.jpg</url>
        <title>Terminator</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greece bids Games farewell</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        The 2004 Olympic Games officially came to an end in Athens with a spectacular closing ceremony on Sunday.
        Greek music and dance kicked off an evening of celebration before the flame was extinguished and the flag lowered.
        A firework display welcomed the athletes into the Olympic Stadium, with double gold-medallist Kelly Holmes carrying Great Britain's flag.
      </description>
      <category>Sport</category>
      <pubDate>29 August 2004</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/greece.jpg</url>
        <title>greece</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mars's Water Could Be Below Surface</title>
      <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      <description>
        Scientifics determined that, of the water and carbon dioxide that once existed on the planet, only a small amount was likely lost to the effects of solar wind over the past 3.5 billion years.
        Scientifics suggest that water and carbon dioxide reservoirs may therefore still exist on or below the Martian surface.
        Further research into the planet's subsurface and atmosphere could reveal critical information about Mars's climate.
      </description>
      <category>Space</category>
      <pubDate>25 January 2006</pubDate>
      <image>
        <url>~/NewsControl/Images/mars.jpg</url>
        <title>Mars</title>
        <link>javascript:void(0)</link>
      </image>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>