<Demos xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="Demos.xsd" ExpandAllDemosAtFirstTime="true" DisableTextWrap="true">
  <DemoProduct Key="DocumentServerMVC" Url="" IsMvc="true" Title="DocumentServer for ASP.NET MVC" NavItemTitle="Document Server Library in MVC" SeoTitle="DevExpress Document Server for ASP.NET MVC" SupportsTheming="false">

    <DownloadUrl>
      http://go.devexpress.com/DevExpressDownload_UniversalTrial.aspx
    </DownloadUrl>

    <BuyUrl>
      http://go.devexpress.com/DevExpress_AspDemos_BuyNow.aspx
    </BuyUrl>

    <DocUrl>
      http://go.devexpress.com/DevExpress_AspDemos_Doc.aspx
    </DocUrl>

    <Intro Title="Introduction" SeoTitle="DocumentServer .NET Library">
      <BannerTitle>
        .NET Document Server
      </BannerTitle>
      <BannerText>
        Automate Excel and Word without using Microsoft Office automation. Read and write XLS, XLSX, CSV, DOC, DOCX and RTF files. Generate barcodes and compressed archives. Generate PDF files from scratch and manipulate existing PDF documents.
      </BannerText>
      <BannerImageUrl>
        ~/Content/VideoBanner.png
      </BannerImageUrl>
      <BannerUrl>
        http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL8h4jt35t1wg72KSHpBJ9VDElNCYdlWMC
      </BannerUrl>
      <DescriptionTitle>
        Welcome to the online demo site of the .NET Document Server Suite
      </DescriptionTitle>
      <Description>
        <![CDATA[
            This website demonstrates some of the many features and capabilities available to you when using our <b>DocumentServer Suite</b>. These features include:
            ]]>
      </Description>
      <DescriptionFooter>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                To view any of the demos within these web pages, use the menu on the left hand side of this page. To learn more about the DevExpress Extensions for ASP.NET MVC, please refer to the following documents:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <a href="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#AspNet/CustomDocument8161">Introduction to DevExpress Extensions for ASP.NET MVC</a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <a href="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#AspNet/CustomDocument8163">How to Start Using DevExpress Extensions in an MVC Web Application</a> 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <a href="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#AspNet/CustomDocument8164">System Requirements for DevExpress MVC Extensions</a>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                If you want to explore the capabilities of these libraries further, we offer a free evaluation version and 
                all our products are backed by a 60 day no questions asked money back guarantee. 
                For assistance, feel free to contact us at <a href="mailto:support@devexpress.com">support@devexpress.com</a>.
            </p>                
            ]]>
      </DescriptionFooter>
    </Intro>
    <DemoGroup Key="SpreadSheet" Title="Spreadsheet">
      <Demo Key="Api" Title="Spreadsheet API" SeoTitle="Spreadsheet API" IsUpdated="true">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo introduces objects and methods available via Spreadsheet API. The TreeView on the right lists the names of actions illustrating API functionality. Click the action and you will see a code snippet and a preview of what the resulting spreadsheet looks like. The parent node indicates the code file containing this method so you can easily locate it within the demo module.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SeeAlso Url="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#DocumentServer/CustomDocument14918" Title="Spreadsheet Fundamentals" />
        <SeeAlso Url="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#DocumentServer/CustomDocument12074" Title="Spreadsheet API Examples" />
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="ChartsApi" Title="Chart API">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo introduces objects and methods available via Spreadsheet Chart API. The TreeView on the right lists the names of actions illustrating API functionality. Click the action and you will see a code snippet and a preview of what the resulting spreadsheet looks like. The parent node indicates the code file containing this method so you can easily locate it within the demo module.</p>]]>
        </Description>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="PivotApi" Title="Pivot Table API">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo introduces objects and methods available via Spreadsheet Pivot Table API. The TreeView on the right lists the names of actions illustrating API functionality. Click the action and you will see a code snippet and a preview of what the resulting spreadsheet looks like. The parent node indicates the code file containing this method so you can easily locate it within the demo module.</p>]]>
        </Description>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="XLExportApi" Title="XL Export API">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo introduces objects and methods available via XL Export API. The TreeView on the right lists the names of actions illustrating API functionality. Click the action and you will see a code snippet. The parent node indicates the code file containing this method so you can easily locate it within the demo module.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/SpreadsheetXLExportApiModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Code/SpreadsheetApi/XLExportExampleCodeEvaluator.cs</SourceFile>
        <SeeAlso Url="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#DocumentServer/CustomDocument114033" Title="XL Export Library Examples" />
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="LoanAmortizationSchedule" Title="Loan Amortization Schedule" SeoTitle="Loan Amortization Schedule Spreadsheet Template" HighlightedIndex="1" HighlightedImageUrl="~/Content/DemoIcons/LoanAmortizationSchedule.png" HighlightedTitle="Loan Amortization Schedule">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates how to use the Spreadsheet API to create a Loan Amortization Schedule spreadsheet template. You can specify the loan amount, duration, interest value and the start date. Click the Download button to get the worksheet.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>Preview image generated on this page may differ slightly from the actual document.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <HighlightedDescription>
          Generate a worksheet template based on the specified parameters.
        </HighlightedDescription>
        <SourceFile>~/Code/SimpleLoanCalculator/DocumentGenerator.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="MailMerge" Title="Mail Merge" SeoTitle="Spreadsheet Mail Merge">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates how to implement a simple data substitution (mail merge) in a spreadsheet. Click the Download button to get the worksheet.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>Preview image generated on this page may differ slightly from the actual document.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Code/MailMerge/DocumentGenerator.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="BreakevenAnalysis" Title="Breakeven Analysis">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo shows the charts embedded in a worksheet. Preview image generated on this page may differ slightly from the actual document.<p>]]>
        </Description>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="EmployeeInformation" Title="Employee Information" SeoTitle="Spreadsheet Employee Information Template">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates how to use the Spreadsheet Document Server functionality to create an Individual Paystubs spreadsheet template that automatically performs specific calculations.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Code/EmployeeInformation/DocumentGenerator.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="ExpenseReport" Title="Expense Report" SeoTitle="Spreadsheet Expense Report Template">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo shows how to create a worksheet template in code at runtime. </p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>Preview image generated on this page may differ slightly from the actual document.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Code/ExpenseReport/DocumentGenerator.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="ShiftSchedule" Title="Shift Schedule" SeoTitle="Spreadsheet Shift Schedule Template">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates how to create a Shift Schedule spreadsheet template. The TOTAL column includes <helplink href="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#DocumentServer/CustomDocument14942">array formulas</helplink> to automatically calculate the total number of work hours per shift by employees.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Code/ShiftSchedule/DocumentGenerator.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="CustomFunction" Title="Custom Function" SeoTitle="Spreadsheet Custom Function">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates how to implement a custom function for use in a spreadsheet. The number is automatically written in words in different cultures.</p>
                   <p>To create a custom function, implement the <helplink href="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#CoreLibraries/DevExpressSpreadsheetFunctionsCustomFunctiontopic">CustomFunction</helplink> interface and add a function to the <helplink href="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#CoreLibraries/DevExpressSpreadsheetIWorkbook_CustomFunctionstopic">Custom Functions collection</helplink>.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Code/CustomFunction/DocumentGenerator.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="CellArt" Title="Cell Art" SeoTitle="Spreadsheet cell art" HighlightedIndex="2" HighlightedImageUrl="~/Content/DemoIcons/SpreadsheetCellArt.png" HighlightedTitle="Spreadsheet Cell Art">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates advanced cell formatting features. You can split an arbitrary image into a set of cells, each of which is the size of a pixel and is colored according to the corresponding pixel of that image. Click the Load Image button to load an image file and click the Export to XLSX button to create a file containing the selected image.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <HighlightedDescription>
          Split an arbitrary image into colored spreadsheet cells.
        </HighlightedDescription>
        <SourceFile>~/Code/CellArt/DocumentGenerator.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
    </DemoGroup>
    <DemoGroup Key="RichEdit" Title="RichEdit">
      <Demo Key="Export" Title="Document Conversion" SeoTitle="Rich Text Editor Document Conversion" HighlightedIndex="3" HighlightedImageUrl="~/Content/DemoIcons/Export.png">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>Use the Rich Edit Document Server to convert a document from one format to another, or print it to PDF.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <HighlightedDescription>
          Convert rich text document to various formats, including PDF.
        </HighlightedDescription>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="MailMerge" Title="Mail Merge" SeoTitle="Rich Text Editor Mail Merge" HighlightedIndex="5" HighlightedImageUrl="~/Content/DemoIcons/RichEditMailMerge.png">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the Mail Merge feature that allows inserting any kind of data from the data source: texts, dates, and even pictures. Select the Employee, the Customer and required file format. Click the Download button to get the document.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <HighlightedDescription>
          Create a mail merge using document template and data from a data table.
        </HighlightedDescription>
        <SeeAlso Url="http://documentation.devexpress.com/#DocumentServer/CustomDocument15278" Title="Mail Merge" />
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="Api" Title="API" SeoTitle="Rich Text Editor API">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo introduces objects and methods available via RichEdit API. The TreeView on the right lists the names of actions illustrating API functionality. Click the action and you will see a code snippet and a preview of what the resulting document looks like. The parent node indicates the code file containing this method so you can easily locate it within the demo module.</p>]]>
        </Description>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="FindAndReplace" Title="Find and Replace" SeoTitle="Rich Text Editor Find and Replace">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo allows you to find and replace characters or text strings in a document.</p>]]>
        </Description>
      </Demo>
    </DemoGroup>
    <DemoGroup Key="Pdf" Title="Pdf">
      <Demo Key="DocumentCreationApi" Title="Document Creation API" SeoTitle="Document Creation API">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the capability to programmatically generate a document layout and bookmarks using PDF document creation API.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>Click the <b>Create and Download</b> button to create a sample document with a dynamically generated layout and bookmarks.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfDocumentCreationAPIModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfModelBase.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="PasswordProtection" Title="Password Protection" SeoTitle="Password Protection">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the capability to protect a document with a password.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To protect a document with a password, do the following.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<ul><li>Specify the owner’s password, and if required, the user’s password for the document using the respective input fields on the right panel.</li>]]>
          <![CDATA[<li>Specify the required user permissions.</li>]]>
          <![CDATA[<li>Click <b>Protect and Download</b> to save the document with the specified protection settings.</li></ul>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfPasswordProtectionModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Pdf/PdfFileView.cshtml</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="Signature" Title="Signature" SeoTitle="Signature">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the capability to apply a digital signature to a document.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To electronically sign this document using a sample certificate, specify the required settings on the right panel and click <b>Sign and Download</b> to save the signed document.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfSignatureModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Pdf/PdfFileView.cshtml</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="FormFlattening" Title="Form Flattening" SeoTitle="Form Flattening" IsNew="true">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the capability of the PDF Document Processor to flatten an interactive form.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To flatten the interactive form, click the “Flatten And Download…” button in the demo options. To load a custom PDF with form fields, click the “Open…” button.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfFormFlatteningModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfModelBase.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Pdf/PdfFileView.cshtml</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="FormFilling" Title="Form Filling" SeoTitle="Form Filling" IsUpdated="true" HighlightedIndex="4" HighlightedImageUrl="~/Content/DemoIcons/FormFilling.png" HighlightedTitle="PDF Form Filling">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[This demo illustrates how to enable the Form Filling feature for the PDF Document Server and programmatically pass values to fill the PDF Form.]]>
          <![CDATA[To see how it works, specify necessary values in the Demo Options and press the Submit button.]]>
        </Description>
        <HighlightedDescription>
          Fill the existing interactive forms.
        </HighlightedDescription>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfFormFillingModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfModelBase.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Pdf/PdfFileView.cshtml</SourceFile>
      </Demo>      
      <Demo Key="PageMerging" Title="Page Merging" SeoTitle="Page Merging">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the capability to merge different documents into a single PDF.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To select PDF files to be merged, click the <b>Browse</b> button.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To upload the selected documents to the demo server, click the <b>Upload</b> button.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To merge the uploaded files and obtain the resulting PDF, click <b>Merge Files and Download</b>.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfPageMergingModel.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="PageDeletion" Title="Page Deletion" SeoTitle="Page Deletion">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the capability to delete pages from PDF.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To delete the currently displayed page from the demo document, click <b>Delete Current Page</b>.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfPageDeletionModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfModelBase.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Pdf/PdfFileView.cshtml</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="FileAttachment" Title="File Attachment" SeoTitle="File Attachment">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the capability to attach files to a document.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To attach the DevExpress logo file to a sample document, click the <b>Attach and Download</b> button.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfFileAttachmentModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfModelBase.cs</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="TextExtraction" Title="Text Extraction" SeoTitle="Text Extraction">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the capability to extract text from PDF.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To view the text extracted from this demo document, press the <b>Extract Text</b> button.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To load a custom PDF, click the <b>Open</b> button.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfTextExtractionModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfModelBase.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Pdf/PdfFileView.cshtml</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="TextSearch" Title="Text Search" SeoTitle="Text Search">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates the capability of the PDF Viewer to search text in a document.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To add context to the search results, use the <b>Word Count</b> option, which displays the specified number of words in the search results.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>In the input box on the demo toolbar enter the text to search and click <b>Search</b>.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>To load a custom PDF, click the <b>Open</b> button on the demo toolbar.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfTextSearchModel.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Models/PdfModelBase.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Pdf/PdfFileView.cshtml</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
    </DemoGroup>
    <DemoGroup Key="BarCode" Title="BarCode">
      <Demo Key="BarCodeVisualization" Title="Bar Code Visualization" SeoTitle="Bar Code Library" HighlightedIndex="6" HighlightedImageUrl="~/Content/DemoIcons/BarCode.png">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo allows you to generate a bar code and set specific options for any of the numerous industry standard barcode types.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <HighlightedDescription>
          Generate a bar code image with the specified parameters.
        </HighlightedDescription>
        <SourceFile>~/App_Data/ExampleCode/BarCodeVisualisation/BarCodeGenerator.cs</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/App_Data/ExampleCode/BarCodeVisualisation/BarCodeGenerator.vb</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
    </DemoGroup>
    <DemoGroup Key="Compression" Title="Compression">
      <Demo Key="Compress" Title="Compression" SeoTitle="Compression and Archive Library" HighlightedIndex="7" HighlightedImageUrl="~/Content/DemoIcons/Compression.png">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo uses the data compression library to zip files on the server. Browse local files and select files to upload. Click Upload and see the list of uploaded files in the info box. Click Compress Files and Download button to get a zipped archive.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <HighlightedDescription>
          Upload files, compress them on the server and download zip archive.
        </HighlightedDescription>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="Decompress" Title="Decompression" SeoTitle="Decompression Examples">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo uses our data compression library to unzip file archives. Browse local files and select zip archive to upload. Click Upload and view archive content. You can click a file link in the list of contents to open the file in a new browser window.</p>]]>
          <![CDATA[<p>Encrypted zip archives are not processed in this demo.</p>]]>
        </Description>
      </Demo>
    </DemoGroup>
    <DemoGroup Key="Miscellaneous" Title="Miscellaneous">
      <Demo Key="EncodingDetection" Title="Encoding Detection" SeoTitle="Encoding Detection">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates how to use our Document Server to automatically detect character encoding for text files. Load one of our test files or any other text file, and see how text is displayed without encoding detection and with it.</p>]]>
        </Description>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="NumberInWords" Title="Number In Words" SeoTitle="Number In Words">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates how to use our Document Server library to write numbers in words. Enter a positive integer number into the editor at the top and review how this number (cardinal and ordinal) is automatically written in words in different cultures.</p>]]>
        </Description>
      </Demo>
      <Demo Key="UnitConversion" Title="Unit Conversion" SeoTitle="Unit Conversion">
        <Description>
          <![CDATA[<p>This demo illustrates how to use our Unit Conversion library to create a simple unit converter. Select a tab and enter value in any available unit of measurement. It is automatically converted to other units of the same physical quantity.</p>]]>
        </Description>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Miscellaneous/UnitConversionDistanceAndSquarePartial.cshtml</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Miscellaneous/UnitConversionForceAndPowerPartial.cshtml</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Miscellaneous/UnitConversionMassPartial.cshtml</SourceFile>
        <SourceFile>~/Views/Miscellaneous/UnitConversionTemperatureAndPressurePartial.cshtml</SourceFile>
      </Demo>
    </DemoGroup>
  </DemoProduct>
  <Search>
    <Synonyms>
      <Group>datasource, databinding, binding, database, databind</Group>
      <Group>eXpress, Persistent, xpo</Group>
    </Synonyms>
    <Exclusions>
      <Words>devexpress, dx, asp, devex, asp.net, demo, demos, web</Words>
      <Prefixes>aspx, asp, xtra, client, dx, web, mvcx</Prefixes>
      <Postfixes>s, ing, control, e</Postfixes>
    </Exclusions>
  </Search>
  <GlobalHeader LogoPlatformSubject="Document Server" LogoPlatformDescription="OFFICE AUTOMATION MADE SIMPLE"/>
</Demos>
